<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jojocomparisons.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jojocomparisons.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-21T12:17:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://jojocomparisons.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diamond is Unbreakable #01 - Jotaro Kujo! Meets Josuke Higashikata]]></title>
    <link href="http://jojocomparisons.github.io/blog/2016/09/21/first-test-post/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-21T00:31:01+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://jojocomparisons.github.io/blog/2016/09/21/first-test-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://jojocomparisons.github.io/images/01-headerJP.png"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hi, and welcome to this thing.
I started doing this because I loved seeing what David production changed for the JoJo Bluray releases, but seeing as there was nobody doing that same job for the Diamond is Unbreakable Blurays, I decided to take on the mantle and fill this niche myself.
tl;dr: if you&rsquo;re here because you&rsquo;re looking for DiU bluray-broadcast comparisons, then you&rsquo;re in the right place.</p>

<p>Alright, let&rsquo;s kick this off with a comparison of Episode #01!
Seeing as this is the first thing they&rsquo;ve aired, it&rsquo;s pretty much a given that the animation was spot-on even in the broadcast version, so don&rsquo;t expect any major changes.
First image is always the broadcast version, while the second is always from the Bluray.</p>

<ul>
<li>The egg in the intro is slightly brighter:</li>
</ul>


<p><video nocontrols autoplay loop preload='auto'>
  <source src='https://my.mixtape.moe/mhtcnq.webm' type='video/webm; codecs="vp8, vorbis"'>
</video>
<video nocontrols autoplay loop preload='auto'>
  <source src='https://my.mixtape.moe/ktpuhq.webm' type='video/webm; codecs="vp8, vorbis"'>
</video></p>

<ul>
<li><p>The hand chopped off by Kira is uncensored:</p></li>
<li><p>Art director 加藤恵 has been shifted from the end credits to the opening credits:</p></li>
<li><p>The episode title is (very) slightly brighter:</p></li>
<li><p>Star Platinum catching Koichi&rsquo;s things is animated more sharply and with brighter colors:</p></li>
<li><p>Jotaro&rsquo;s coattails are redrawn to be slightly less elevated and more natural-looking:</p></li>
<li><p>The transition into this scene of the blonde punk grabbing the turtle is a bit longer and clearer:</p></li>
<li><p>The aforementioned blonde punk has a very very slightly darker right eyebrow:</p></li>
<li><p>Koichi has a thinner outer border in this scene:</p></li>
<li><p>Koichi&rsquo;s mouth has been properly shaded here:</p></li>
<li><p>This scene has an extra noise layer on top:</p></li>
<li><p>Josuke has a bighter and pinker aura in this scene:</p></li>
<li><p>This scene has brighter colors:</p></li>
<li><p>Crazy Diamond&rsquo;s punch has been uncensored (the second censoring is a bit hard to spot):</p></li>
<li><p>Several people have been removed from the end credits:</p></li>
<li><p>As stated earlier, 加藤恵 is no longer in the ending credits:</p></li>
<li><p>The &ldquo;next time&rdquo; card is slightly brighter:</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And that&rsquo;s all for this episode, I&rsquo;m afraid. As I said earlier, this first one didn&rsquo;t have many changes: mostly colors, cleaner animations and a couple of very minor fixes.
Tune in next time for the Dog Eating Extravaganza as we delve into the Episode #02 comparison.
Bye!</p>

<p>P.S.: As of the moment of writing, only the raws for episodes 01 to 03 are out, so that will be the first batch of comparisons to come out. Expect the next update tomorrow or the day after, and then all other episodes as the raws come out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
